chrono24.com 2016-06-03

# Chrono24 - Datenschutz

## Data Privacy Policy

As of: February 2016

Please note that this is a translation of our German Data Privacy Policy only. Our Data Privacy Policy only applies as defined in the [German version](http://www.chrono24.de/info/datenschutz.htm).  

We, Chrono24 GmbH, Haid-und-Neu-Str. 18, 76131 Karlsruhe, Germany (hereinafter referred to as **"Chrono24"** ), operate the under www.chrono24.com available online marketplace for premium watches (hereinafter referred to as **"platform"** ). We are therefore responsible for the collection, processing and use of your personal data within the meaning of the German Data Privacy Act (BDSG) and the German Telemedia Act (TMG). The correct handling of your personal data is particularly important to us. Therefore, we are pleased to provide you with information on how your personal data is handled. 

We offer you the possibility to use a mobile device to access our platform or to use our services either via a mobile application (app) or via a website optimized for mobile devices. The provisions of this Data Privacy Policy shall also apply to mobile access and the use of mobile devices. Reference is made to this Data Privacy Policy in all mobile applications and on all websites optimized for mobile devices. 

**We use your personal data in compliance with the applicable data privacy provisions. Below we will describe what data we collect, how we use it and what rights you have in terms of our use of your data.**

**By using our platform you consent to the collection, processing and use of your personal data.**

**1.** **Scope and purpose of the collection, processing and use of personal data**

**a.** **When visiting our website**

When you visit our website, our servers temporarily save every access in a log file. The following data are automatically recorded without any action on your part and stored until such time as the profile is deleted:

  * the IP address of the accessing computer,
  * the date and time of access,
  * the name and URL of the accessed file,
  * the website from which you accessed our website (referrer),
  * the session ID,
  * the user agent.

This data is collected and processed for the purposes of facilitating use of our website (creating the connection), guaranteeing long-term system security and stability and optimizing our web service, and for internal statistical purposes. The IP address will be evaluated only in the event of attacks on our network infrastructure, for statistical purposes and to assert or defend against legal claims. Subsequently your personal data will be deleted. 

We use cookies and web analytics and marketing services when visiting our website. You can find out more about this in Sections 7 and 9.

**b.** **When registering as a user on the Platform**

Buyers and private sellers can create a user account on our platform. To create an account, submission of the below-mentioned data is required. Collection and processing of this data is necessary

  * to verify the identity of the contractual partner,
  * to conclude, to design, to process and to amend the contract with you regarding the use of our platform and offered services,
  * to check plausibility of submitted data,
  * to contact you in case of further enquiry.

**aa.** **myChrono24 user account**

To register as a user and create a user account the following data are required:

  * your e-mail address,
  * a user-defined password.

This data are necessary to log into your user account.

Additional non-mandatory data:

  * first and last name,
  * address (street, postal code, city, country),
  * phone number.

Submission of this non-mandatory data improves the possibility to contact you.

**bb.** **Private Seller**

If you wish to publish offers on the platform as a private seller, you need to set up a user account. To publish an offer on the platform the following data is required: 

  * first and last name,
  * address (street, postal code, city, country),
  * phone number.

**cc.** **Dealer**

To register as a dealer, following date are required:

  * trade name,
  * Contact information (first and last name),
  * address (street, postal code, city, country),
  * phone number,
  * e-mail address,
  * user-defined user name,
  * user-defined password

Additional non-mandatory data:

  * telefax,
  * mobile number,
  * URL.

Submission of this non-mandatory data improves the possibility to contact you.

**c.** **When using the portal as a registered user/dealer**

When using the portal as a registered user, we collect data for statistical purposes and for the purpose of optimizing our web services. In particular, the following data is collected: 

  * duration of membership
  * type, frequency and intensity of use of the website
  * history of selected offers, brands and offerors.

**If you do not want to participate in our programs to personalize our performance and advertisement any longer, you can revoke to your participation through your user account.**

**d.** **When using the Trusted Check Out Services**

A user account is required to initiate and to conclude contracts with a dealer via our Trusted Checkout service. Additionally, following data is required:

  * First and last name,
  * address (street, postal code, city, country),
  * telephone number.

We need this data to verify the identity of the contractual partner of the dealer, to constitute the purchase contract, to support the contextual form of the purchase contract, to support the processing of the purchase contract and to contact you in case of further enquiry. Data will also be transmitted to the dealer for this purpose if you request an offer to buy or conclude a purchase contract with this dealer.

**e.** **Information about Chrono24 by e-mail**

**We endeavor to improve and enhance our platform constantly.In order to inform you about Chrono24, our services and innovations, which are interesting to you as a user, private seller or dealer, we will occasionally send e-mails to the e-mail address you provided.You can object the use of your e-mail address for this purpose anytime (only basic transmission fees apply).Please send your objection to if you do not want to receive information about Chrono24.Objection or absence of consent does neither affect conclusion of contract nor use of the platform or offered services. **

**f.** **Newsletter**

In order to provide you with information via e-mail we will send you our newsletter. You will receive our newsletter only if you have expressly and specifically agreed.

You can unsubscribe by sending an e-mail to  or via the link at the end of each newsletter.

**g.** **When communicating with us or other users via the platform**

You can use the contact form to get in touch with dealers/private sellers via the platform. This requires entry of the following data:

  * first and last name,
  * e-mail-address,
  * phone number,
  * message.

We will save this data and in case of messages to private sellers or dealers transmit message to these users. We reserve the right to scan and analyze messages.

This data is collected and processed for purposes of fraud prevention, to personalize our services and advertisements and to optimize communication and customer service.

**By using our platform you consent that we may scan and analyze your messages, either manually or automatically.**

We will not scan or analyze your messages in order to send you advertising messages from third parties. We will not disclose the findings of our scans or analyses to third parties.

**You can object the use of your data for this purpose anytime. Please send your objection to support@chrono24.com if you do not want us to scan or analyze your messages.**

In case of objection, the use of communications services on our platform is excluded due to technical reasons.

**h.** **When leaving a comment in our magazine**

You can comment on articles in our magazine at [http://www.chrono24.com/magazine/](http://www.chrono24.com/magazine). Required information: 

  * first and last name,
  * e-mail-address,
  * comment.

We need your name and e-mail-address in order to get in touch with and to pursue possible legal infringements. This data will not be published.

**2.** **Disclosure of Data to Third Parties for Contractual Purposes**

We will share your personal data with third parties only if you have expressly agreed to this, if we are under a legal obligation to do so, or if this is required in order to assert our rights, in particular to enforce claims arising from the contractual relationship.

**3.** **Visibility of Your Data for Third Parties**

**a)** **Users and Private Sellers**

Personal data which is saved in your user account (myChrono24) is not accessible for third parties unless you publish offers on the platform. When you publish offers on the platform as private seller, both registered and non-registered user can access your offeror’s data only if you expressly consented. 

**b)** **Express-Sales**

The Express-Sale Service provides users the free-of-charge option to offer sales objects on the platform (hereinafter “”Request For Proposal” or “RFP”). RFP are submitted anonymously and are visible on the platform for dealers using the Express-Sale Service only. Correspondence between dealer and you is carried out anonymously via the user account. An anonymized version of correspondence between dealer and user can be accessed by dealers using the Express-Sale Service.

You can access dealers’ specifications by pressing the button “Proceed to Acceptance”. In this case, the dealer is provided with your specifications as stored in user account (name, address, phone number, fax, e-mail-address).  
The user’s ITT RFP is deleted from platform, as soon as the user is provided with dealer’s specifications; in this case, the user rejects other dealers’ offers. 

**c)** **Dealers**

If you are registered as dealer and publish offers on the platform, both registered and non-registered users can access your data as listed in Sec. 1b) cc). You can exclude your address from accessible data during registration or afterwards within your profile.

**4.** **Registration with Co-operation Partner (Auctionata) of Chrono24**

Chrono24 and ISA Auctionata Auktionen AG, Kurfürstendamm 212, D-10719 Berlin, Germany (hereinafter „Auctionata“) jointly offer auction platforms for watches accessible at the URL [http://auctionata.com](http://auctionata.com/) and <http://chrono24.auctionata.com/>. You can register with our cooperative partners Auctionata using the data of your Chrono24 user account. If you send a registration request to Auctionata, Chrono24 will forward data listed below to complete your Auctionata registration form, provided you are simultaneously logged in with your Chrono24 user account. 

  * Trade name,
  * first and last name,
  * address (street, postal code, city, country),
  * phone number,
  * fax number,
  * e-mail address.

If you do not confirm registration or delete or amend data input in the registration form, Auctionata will delete your data immediately.

Please also observe data policy of Auctionata: [https://auctionata.com/en/privacy-policy](http://auctionata.com/en/privacy-policy).

There is no additional data exchange/reconciliation between Chrono24 and Auctionata.

**5.** **Right to Information, Deletion and Correction**

You have a right to information regarding the personal data stored under your name and you can review and change these data after logging into our platform. Formal information requests require written form and proof of identity.

You can delete or adjust your personal data or your user account anytime. For this purpose send an e-mail to support@chrono24.com or use the contact form. Please note that our services may not be available to you or not in full extent after deleting your data. Uploaded content (e.g. comments) will remain accessible.

**6.** **Data security**

We use appropriate technical and organizational security measures to protect your personal data stored by us against manipulation, partial or total loss, and unauthorized access by third parties. Our security measures are being continually improved in line with technological developments.

When registering as a user you need to type in your personal password to access your user account. Please treat your access data as confidential and close the browser window after ending communication with us, particularly if you share the computer with others.

We also take in-house data protection very seriously. Our employees and the service providers commissioned by us are obligated to maintain confidentiality and comply with data privacy provisions.

**7.** **Cookies**

Cookies help in many different ways to make your visit to our platform easier, more comfortable and more intuitive. Cookies are alpha-numerical information files that your web browser automatically stores on the hard drive of your computer when you visit our Internet site. Cookies do not harm the hard drive on your computer.

We use cookies, for example, to identify you as registered user without logging in. The use of the cookies does not allow us to obtain new personal data about you as an online visitor. The majority of Internet browsers accept cookies automatically. However, you can configure your browser to reject cookies or to notify you whenever you receive a new cookie.

Third-party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a your prior visits to our website. You can object collection and storage of data anytime with future effect.

If you prefer not to receive interest-based advertising, you can deactivate the use of cookies by Google for these purposes at <https://www.google.de/settings/ads>. You can find more information on that at [www.google.de/privacy/ads](http://www.google.de/privacy/ads). Further information on the provisions of Google is available at [www.google.com/intl/de/privacy](http://www.google.com/intl/de/privacy). Alternatively, users can deactivate the use of third-party cookies by visiting the Network Advertising deactivation site at [www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

Please note that deactivating cookies does not effect your browser to remain deactivated after deleting the deactivation cookies.

Deactivation of cookies can lead to you not being able to use all of the functions of our platform. More information about deactivating cookies can be found at: [http://www.meine-cookies.org](http://www.meine-cookies.org/).

**8.** **Links**

This Data Privacy Policy does not cover websites that are linked to from our website. We have no influence over whether our data privacy and security standards are upheld by these sites. The operators of linked sites are solely responsible for the content thereof.

**9.** **Web analytics**

**a.** **General information**

To shape our website according to needs and to continually optimize our service, we use web analysis services (“Google Universal Analytics”, a web analytics service of Google Inc. and “MobileAppTracking by Tune” as well as other services). Within this context, pseudonymized usage profiles are created and small text files that are saved on your computer (“cookies”) are used. Unless otherwise specified, the following shall apply.

The information concerning your use of this website that is generated by cookies, includes

  * browser type/version,
  * operating system used,
  * referrer URL (the page visited previously),
  * host name of the accessing computer (IP address),
  * time of server access,

and is transferred to servers in the USA and stored there. The information is used to evaluate use of the website, to compile reports on website activity and to provide further services associated with website and Internet use for the purposes of market research and needs-based design of these web pages. This information may also be forwarded to third parties as appropriate, insofar as this is prescribed by law or insofar as these parties process the data on behalf of the commissioning party. Your IP address will not in any case be associated with other data from Google. IP addresses are anonymized to exclude all possibility of such association (IP masking).

The user can prevent the installation of cookies by adjusting his/her browser accordingly; in this case, however, not all functions of the website may be available to the user to their full extent.

Alternatively, the web analytics services offer various options to prevent the information generated by a cookie from being collected and processed. Further information about the various options can be found in the paragraphs below and – particularly – in Sec. 9g).

**b.** **Hotjar**

We use the web analytics service of Hotjar Ltd., Level 2, St Julians Business Centre, 3, Elia Zammit Street, St. Julians STJ 1000, Malta. Cookies used by Hotjar are deleted automatically after 365 days. [Here](http://docs.hotjar.com/docs/cookies-stored-by-hotjar) you can find out more about cookies used by Hotjar. 

Information collected by cookies is transferred to servers in the Europe and stored there. The information is used to record use of the website in anonymized way, e.g. mouse movements and clicks. Use of keyboard during entry of passwords or payment details is not recorded. Hotjar will use this information for the purpose of improving the usability of our websites. 

Collection and evaluation of this data will not enable us to identify you personally. Information is anonymized by a so-called UUID (Universally Unique Identifier) which allows us to track returning users without knowing their identity. 

We do not disclose information to third parties, unless required to do so by law or third parties process the information on our behalf (e.g. computer center). 

If you do not want Hotjar to collect information about your use of our websites, you can either change the relevant cookie settings in your browser or deactivate execution of JavaScripts in your browser or apply browser add ons (q.v. Sec. 9g). 

Further information about data protection during use of Hotjar can be found in the [Privacy Policy of Hotjar](https://www.hotjar.com/privacy). 

**c.** **Optimizely**

We use Optimizely, a web analytics service of Optimizely Inc, offering a range of website analytics services for A/B and multivariate testing purposes. Optimizely does not store or process personally identifiable information about you. 

You can deactivate data collection and processing of your use of our website anytime with future effect. There is an opt-out cookie that prevents the future collection of your data by Optimizely when visiting this website (q.v. Sec. 9g). We do not disclose information to third parties, unless required to do so by law or third parties process the information on our behalf (e.g. computer center). 

Further information about data protection of Optimizely and the functioning of the service can be found in their Privacy Policy. 

**d.** **“Google Universal Analytics”**

We use Google Analytics, including the functions of Google Universal Analytics. This enables us to optimize the analysis of the visits to our site. Google Universal Analytics allows us to analyze the activities of our sites across multiple devices (e.g. access with laptops or tablets). This is made possible by assigning an ser ID to a user. Such an assignment will occur if you register for an account on the marketplace operated by chrono24.com or log into your account.

This user ID together with the behavior of the user on our marketplace during the assignment is forwarded to the Google servers. If you visit this website during a session, your behavior on this website will also be transmitted. However, no personal data or information will be forwarded to Google. The duration of a session does not exceed four hours.

Google then analyzes the user's behavior for us and provides us with reports about the user’s activities. We personally create no user profiles from the reports received by Google that would enable specific users and their personal data to be identified.

Although additional functions are added to Google Analytics with Universal Analytics, this does not mean that a limitation of data protection measures, such as IP masking or browser add-on, are connected (see 9a).

Further information about Google Universal Analytics can be found on the Google Analytics help pages.

**e.** **“Google Analytics Advertising Features”**

We use Google Universal Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Every user is assigned with a user ID when registering or first logging in. This user ID and information about your use of our website, not including personal data of the user, will generally be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information on behalf of the operator of this website for the purpose of evaluating your use of our website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing them other services relating to website activity and internet usage.

An IP-anonymization is activated on our website, ensuring that no one will be able to determine your identity. We do not use the reports we receive from Google Inc. to create user profiles which allow an assignment to users and their personal data.

**f.** **Mailing analytics**

We use e-mail-analytic services of Litmus Software Inc., located in the USA. Litmus collects statistical information of our e-mails delivery and evaluates this information for us. This allows us to identify problems concerning our newsletter and contained links. Litmus enables us to trace which content sparks particular interest. This allows us to adjust our newsletter to particular interests.

When using the services of Litmus we do not determine your identity. Information will not be assigned to certain e-mail recipients. We only create pseudonymized user profiles not allowing identification.

If you do not want Litmus to collect information about e-mails sent to you, please send an e-mail to .

**f.** **Mailing analytics**

We use e-mail-analytic services of Litmus Software Inc., located in the USA. Litmus collects statistical information of our e-mails delivery and evaluates this information for us. This allows us to identify problems concerning our newsletter and contained links. Litmus enables us to trace which content sparks particular interest. This allows us to adjust our newsletter to particular interests.

When using the services of Litmus we do not determine your identity. Information will not be assigned to certain e-mail recipients. We only create pseudonymized user profiles not allowing identification.

If you do not want Litmus to collect information about e-mails sent to you, please send an e-mail to .

**g.** **Objection**

You can object to the compilation of user profiles anytime.

If you wish to object please follow the instructions of the provider of the respective web analytics service:

  * You can find instructions for preventing your data being processed by the web analytics service of Google Universal Analytics at <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de>
  * You can find instructions for preventing your data being processed by MobileAppTracking by Tune at <http://optoutmobile.com/optout/index.html>
  * You can prevent your data being processed by Hotjar by installation and use of a browser-add-on like [Ghostery](https://www.ghostery.com/).
  * You can prevent your data being processed by Optimizely by using a opt-out-cookie. Find an instruction at <https://www.optimizely.com/de/opt_out/>.

We use the tool Crashlytics to collect crash reports and improve the stability of our app. According to the provider of Crashlytics no personal data is collected or disclosed. According to Crashlytics, crash reports are delivered only, including time of crash, receiving device and location. Further information can be found in the privacy policy of Crashlytics at <http://try.crashlytics.com/terms/privacy-policy.pdf>. 

**10.** **Social media plugins**

**a.** **Facebook**

Facebook social plug-ins are used on our Internet sites to make the website a more personal experience, using the “LIKE” or “SHARE” buttons. This is a service offered by the American company Facebook Inc. (1601 Willow Rd, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA).

When you call up a page of our web site that includes such a plug-in, your browser creates an automatic connection with the Facebook servers. The content of the plug-in is transmitted by Facebook directly to your browser and embedded from there into the website.

By connecting the plug-in, Facebook receives information that your browser has called up the corresponding page of our web presence, even if you do not have a Facebook account or are not at present logged in to Facebook. This information (including your IP address) is transmitted directly from your browser to a server of Facebook in the USA and stored there.

If you are logged in on Facebook, Facebook is able to match your visit to our website directly with your Facebook account. When you interact with the plug-ins, for instance by using the “LIKE” or “SHARE” buttons, the relevant information is then likewise sent directly to a Facebook server and stored there. The information is moreover published on Facebook and displayed to your Facebook friends.

Facebook may use this information for advertising and market research purposes and to make the Facebook pages more user-friendly. To this end, usage, interests and relationship- profiles are created by Facebook, in order for instance to evaluate your use of our website with regard to the advertisements displayed to you on Facebook, to inform other Facebook users about your activities on our website and to provide further services related to your use of Facebook.

If you do not wish Facebook to match the data collected via our web presence to your Facebook account, you must log out of Facebook before visiting our website.

To find out more about the purpose and scope of data collection and further processing and use of data by Facebook as well as your rights in this regard and how you can configure your account to protect your privacy, please refer to the [Facebook Data Use Policy](http://www.facebook.com/policy.php).

**b.** **Twitter**

Plug-ins by the short message network Twitter Inc., 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco CA 94103, USA are integrated into our Internet sites. You can identify the Twitter plug-ins (tweet button) from the Twitter logo on our website. You can find an overview of information on the tweet button. When you call up a page of our web presence containing such a plug-in, a direct connection is created between your browser and the Twitter server. Twitter is thus informed that you have visited our site with your IP address. If you click on the Twitter tweet button while you are logged in to your Twitter account, you can link the content of our pages to your Twitter profile, which means that Twitter can match your visit to our website to your user account. We would point out that we, as the provider of the pages, have no knowledge of the content of the data transmitted or how it is used by Twitter. You can find out more information on this [here](http://twitter.com/privacy). 

If you do not wish Twitter to match your visit to our website to your account, you should please log out of your Twitter user account.

**c.** **Google+**

Our websites use the +1 button of the social network Google+, offered by the American company Google Inc. („Google“), Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. You can identify he button by the symbol “g+1“ on a white or colored background.

Every page of our website that contains such a button will lead to your browser loading and optically rendering said button from a Google server. Therefore, we cannot influence which data Google collects through the button. According to Google data, such as your IP-address, is only collected if you if you click the +1 button while logged into your Google+ (Google Plus) account.

The following web address contains Google’s privacy policy, including further information on the collection and use of personal information by Google, on your respective rights and on account preferences available in order to maintain a reasonable degree of privacy: <https://www.google.com/intl/de/+/policy/+1button.html>

Please log out of your Google+ account before using our website if you do not wish Google to collect data about your use of our website and link them with the data of your Google account

**11.** **Right to Information, Correction, Blocking and Deletion**

You have the right to information regarding the personal data stored under your name as well as a right to correct incorrect data, or to block and delete such data.

To get information on your personal data, to have incorrect data corrected, to have data blocked or deleted or for further questions on the use of your personal data please contact:

Tel.: +49 721 480889-80

Fax: +49 721 480889-88

E-Mail: 

You can review and edit your data anytime by logging into our website with your log-in-data.

**12.** **Validity of the data privacy policy**

This Data Privacy Policy is current and is dated February 2016.

Our Data Privacy Policy can be viewed and printed anytime on our website, at 

<http://www.chrono24.de/info/datenschutz.htm>

**Chrono24 GmbH**
